Guide to the Nina Rosenblum Papers MSS.558
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XIX. Ordinary Miracles: The Photo League's New York, 1942-2014; 13.13 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes, 6 record cartons, 1 medium flat box, 3 cassette boxes, 1 card box, 3 small flat boxes, and 1 flat file folder; 22 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 7 VHS; 11 16mm_film_reels; 8 audiocassette; 10 
  - Subseries XIX.D. Production Materials, 1989-2012; 11.52 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 6 record cartons, 3 cassette boxes, 1 card box, 2 small flat boxes, and 1 medium flat box; 16 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 2 VHS; 11 16mm_film_reels; 8 audiocassette; 10 DAT; 5 Digital_Betacam; 15 DVCAM; 33 Mi
    - Film and Video Recordings
      - New York Public Library
        - NYPL Photo League 2 -- Digital Master, undated (Box 22, Minidv 558.0046)
        - NYPL Photo League 3 -- Digital Master, undated (Box 22, Minidv 558.0047)
      - Paul Strand and Walter Rosenblum
        - Italy -- Tape 1, undated (Box 40, Minidv 558.0086)
        - Italy -- Tape 2, undated (Box 40, Minidv 558.0085)
        - Italy -- Tape 3, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0068)
        - Italy -- Tape 5, undated (Box 40, Minidv 558.0090)
        - Paul Waller, Strand, and Rosenblum -- Tape 1, January 24, 2011 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0087)
        - Tape 2, January 24, 2011 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0084)
        - Tape 3, January 24, 2011 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0088)
        - Tape 4, January 24, 2011 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0098)
        - Tape 4, undated (Box 40, Minidv 558.0099)
        - Tape 5, January 24, 2011 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0089)
        - Walter Rosenblum on Strand -- Master -- Tape 3, undated (Box 60, Vhs 558.0254)
      - Rebecca Lepkoff
        - In Her Studio and Mary, December 16, 2000 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0091)
        - Looks at Photos in Her Studio, December 16, 2000 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0077)
        - Tape 4A, October 15, 1999 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0559)
      - "RG"
        - Tape 1, February 26, 2000 (Box 25, Digital betacam 558.0108)
        - Tape 2, February 26, 2000 (Box 25, Digital betacam 558.0107)
        - Tape 3, February 26, 2000 (Box 25, Digital betacam 558.0103)
        - Tape 4, February 26, 2000 (Box 25, Digital betacam 558.0106)
      - Rosalie Walter
        - Tape 1, September 26, 2000 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0311)
        - Tape 2, September 26, 2000 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0317)
        - Tape 3, September 26, 2000 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0314)
      - Sol Libsohm
        - #2, June 25, 1999 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0097)
        - Video Recording, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0067)
      - Trailers, undated; FA_MSS_558_ER_125
      - "UB"
        - Tape 1, October 14, 1999 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0308)
        - Tape 1A, October 14, 1999 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0312)
        - Tape 2A, October 14, 1999 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0315)
        - Tape 2B, October 14, 1999 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0313)
        - Tape 3A -- Sid Koerner, October 15, 1999; F84 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0309)
      - Walter Rosenblum
        - Octavio and WR -- #1, January 13, 2003 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0075)
        - Octavio and WR -- #2, January 13, 2003 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0076)
        - Walter Rosenblum Films, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0072)
      - Weegee Clip, 2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_126
      - Zero Mostel, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0070)
    - Notes, 1999-2011 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - 99 Photo League Reunion
      - Camera Rolls 1-2, October 2, 1999; cuid41404 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0021)
      - Camera Rolls 3-4, October 2, 1999; cuid41410 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0028)
      - Camera Rolls 5-6, October 2, 1999; cuid41406 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0023)
      - Camera Rolls 7-8, October 2, 1999; cuid41405 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0022)
      - Camera Rolls 9-10, October 2, 1999; cuid41409 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0027)
      - Camera Rolls 11-12, October 2, 1999; cuid41408 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0026)
      - Camera Rolls 13-14, October 2, 1999; cuid41407 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0025)
      - Camera Rolls 15-16, undated; cuid41414 (Box 54, 16mm film reels 558.0024)
      - Camera Rolls 17-18, October 2, 1999; cuid41413 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0030)
      - Camera Rolls 19-20, October 2, 1999; cuid41411 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0029)
      - Camera Roll 21, October 2, 1999; cuid41412 (Box 55, 16mm film reels 558.0034)
      - Contact Sheets and Slides, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - CR 1-4 -- Sound Rolls N1-N2, October 28, 1999 (Box 37, Dat 558.0061)
      - CR 5-8 -- Sound Rolls N2-N4, October 28, 1999 (Box 37, Dat 558.0065)
      - CR 9-12 -- Sound Rolls N4-N6, October 28, 1999 (Box 37, Dat 558.0064)
      - CR 13-16 -- Sound Rolls 9-10, October 28, 1999 (Box 37, Dat 558.0062)
      - CR 17-20 -- Sound Rolls 10-13, October 28, 1999 (Box 37, Dat 558.0063)
      - CR 21 -- Sound Rolls 13-14, October 28, 1999 (Box 37, Dat 558.0059)
      - Morris and Jack -- Harlem Document, circa 1999 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0310)
      - Negatives, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Photographs
        - Electronic Records, circa 1999-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_65
        - Prints, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 3, Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Sound Rolls 1-2, circa 1999 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0048)
      - Sound Rolls 3-4, circa 1999 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0052)
      - Sound Rolls 5-6, circa 1999 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0050)
      - Sound Rolls 7-8, circa 1999 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0049)
      - Sound Rolls 9-10, October 28, 1999 (Box 37, Dat 558.0060)
      - Sound Rolls 9-10, circa 1999 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0051)
      - Sound Rolls 11-12, circa 1999 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0053)
      - Sound Rolls 13-14, circa 1999 (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0054)
      - Tape 1 -- CR 1-4, October 14, 1999 (Box 25, Betacam sp 558.0113)
      - Tape 2 -- CR 5-8, October 14, 1999 (Box 25, Betacam sp 558.0115)
      - Tape 3 -- CR 9-12, October 15, 1999 (Box 25, Betacam sp 558.0111)
      - Tape 4 -- CR 13-16, October 15, 1999 (Box 25, Betacam sp 558.0112)
      - Tape 5 -- CR 17-20, October 15, 1999 (Box 25, Betacam sp 558.0114)
      - Tape 6 -- CR 21, October 15, 1999 (Box 25, Betacam sp 558.0104)
      - Video Recording, October 23, 1999 (Box 22, Dvcam 558.0560)
    - Production Book, 1999-2011 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Proposals and Treatments, 1989-1999 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Scene Lists, Music, and Credits, 2011-2012 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Tape Logs, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Voiceovers and Narrations -- Scripts, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Subseries XIX.E. Research Materials, 1932-2010; 3.56 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes, 1 record carton, and 1 small flat box; 6 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 5 VHS; 12.32 Gigabytes in 654 computer files
    This subseries includes research materials used in the making of the film. Materials include archival copies of Executive Committee minutes and exhibitions sponsored by the League; bibliographies; Freedom of Information Act files; interviews and lectures given by Walter Rosenblum about the League; and correspondence with Photo League members.
    - Articles and Papers, 1935-2003 (Box 15, Folder 8-9, Box 16, Folder 1, Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Audio Recordings
      - Alfred Stieglitz Symposium -- "A Photographer's Place" -- Emmanuel Benson, Ralph Steiner, and Walter Rosenblum -- Tape 11, November 18, 1962 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0482)
      - Alfred Stieglitz Symposium -- "A Photographer's Place" -- Tape 12, November 18, 1962 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0483)
      - "Famous Photographers Tell How", undated; FA_MSS_558_ER_108
      - Oceanhill/Brownsville Parent Discussion -- Belle Barth, undated (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0484)
      - Paul Strand, April 25, 1975 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0485)
      - Peter Magubane, June 23, 1984 (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0502)
      - Strand Archives -- Tape #7, undated (Box 33, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0478)
    - Bibliographies, Chronologies, and Notes, 1978-1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Exhibitions and Books on the Photo League, 1948-2010 (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
    - Freedom of Information Act/FBI Files, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 6, Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Photo League
      - Archival Material -- Executive Committee, Membership, and Press, 1939-1950 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Photo League Bulletin Board, 2002-2008 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Photo League Members -- Press, Correspondence, and Photographs, 1932-2007 (Box 17, Folder 4-7, Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Photo League School, 1937-1950 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Photo Notes, 1938-1950 (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
    - Photographs, 1934-1982; FA_MSS_558_ER_69
    - Walter Rosenblum
      - Correspondence and Exhibitions with Photo League, 1944-2001 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Interviews about Photo League, 1971-1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Museum of Photographic Arts -- Tape 6 -- Archival Footage, circa 1993 (Box 60, Vhs 558.0203)
      - Museum of Photographic Arts -- Walkthrough for Docents -- Archival Footage, November 19, 1993 (Box 60, Vhs 558.0202)
      - Rochester Institute of Technology -- Archival Footage, February 6, 1991 (Box 60, Vhs 558.0201)
      - Rochester Institute of Technology -- Tape 4 -- Archival Footage, February 6, 1991 (Box 60, Vhs 558.0207)
      - Tremaine Gallery -- Hotchkiss School -- Archival Footage, undated (Box 60, Vhs 558.0209)
      - Writing and Lectures about Photo League, 1942-1999 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Subseries XIX.F. Screenings and Festivals, 2011-2013; .98 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 small flat box, and 1 medium flat box; 1.93 Gigabytes in 2 computer files
    This subseries includes materials rleated to the screening of the film and participation in film festivals; materials include correspondence, schedules, and festival programs.
    - Electronic Recordings, 2013; FA_MSS_558_ER_70
    - Poster, 2012 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Programs and Schedules, 2011-2013 (Box 19, Folder 10, Box 20, Folder 7)
- Series XX. Unrealized Projects and Tributes, 1981-2014; 10.19 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, 3 cassette boxes, 1 LP box, 2 small flat boxes, and 2 card boxes; 4 U-matic; 4 audiocassette; 4 Betacam; 2 DVCPRO; 43 MiniDV; 2 VHS; 4 Betacam_SP; 1 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 171.05 Gigabytes in 891 computer files
  This series consists of materials related to films that were early demos, incomplete, or unidentified. Additionally, there are two tribute films made for friends and colleagues of Rosenblum. Materials related to the early, incomplete, and unidentified films cover topics and figures such as Ann Ligouri, a sports broadcaster; bodybuilding; same-sex marriage; and the artwork of Tommy Tune. Materials include research files (such as articles, legal case files, and correspondence), film clips, photographs, and interviews. The tribute films honor Bill Miles, who co-produced and co-directed Liberators and The Untold West: Black West, and Dennis Watlington, who wrote and co-produced The Untold West: Black West and wrote Twin Lenses. Materials related to these tributes consist of biographical information (such as resumes), video recordings of Miles's other films, video recordings of Watlington's book tour, and, in the case of Miles, a memorial program.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic and alphanumerically within each one.
  - Bill Miles Tribute
    - Biographical Information and Memorial Program, 2012 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Electronic Records, 2010-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_96
    - Video Recording, 2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_114
  - "Friends of Dennis Watlington"
    - Electronic Records, 2006-2014; FA_MSS_558_ER_92
    - Postcard, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Video Recordings, circa 2006-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_113
  - Unrealized and Unidentified Projects
    - Ann Ligouri Project -- Electronic Records, 2008-2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_95
    - Ann Ligouri Project -- Clipping, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Blewish", 2006; FA_MSS_558_ER_91
    - Bodybuilding Project -- Austen with Friends -- Roid Rage -- Raw Footage Selects -- Part 2, undated (Box 38, Vhs 558.0181)
    - Bodybuilding Project -- Queens Shoot #2, undated (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0459)
    - Bodybuilding Project -- Queens Shoot #3, undated (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0454)
    - Bodybuilding Project -- Queens Shoot #4, undated (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0458)
    - Congregation Shearith Israel Project, 2003; FA_MSS_558_ER_97
    - Eric Hill Project, 2007; FA_MSS_558_ER_128
    - "Fool for Love" -- Dub -- #6, January 6, 1981 (Box 24, U-matic 558.0566)
    - "Fool for Love" -- Final Version -- Cut Master, undated (Box 38, U-matic 558.0178)
    - "Fool for Love" -- Dub -- #7, undated (Box 24, U-matic 558.0569)
    - Grambs Aronson Project, 1996-2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_98
    - Italian Photographers Project -- Electronic Records, 2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_99
    - Italian Photographers Project -- Silvia Baraldini Interview -- Video Recording, undated (Box Shared Fales 121, U-matic 558.0004)
    - Italian Photographers Project -- Video Recordings, 2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_115
    - Jacob Lawrence Project -- "The Trumpet Sounds within My Soul", 2011; FA_MSS_558_ER_100
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Budget and Release, 2009 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Doug at Home, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0194)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Electronic Records, 2009-2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_93
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Construction #1, April 10, 2009 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0196)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Construction #2, April 10, 2009 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0200)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Mike and Doug, April 30, 2009 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0190)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Mike and Doug 1, April 30, 2009 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0198)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Mike and Doug 2, May 7, 2009 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0193)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Mike and Doug 2 -- First with Lights, May 7, 2009 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0191)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Prop 8 #1, May 16, 2009 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0189)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Prop 8 #2, May 26, 2009 (Box 22, Minidv 558.0197)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Women #1, March 19, 2009 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0081)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Kens Shoot -- Women #2, March 19, 2009 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0080)
    - "Marriage for Some" -- Mike, Doug, and Officiator, June 10, 2009 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0199)
    - Maureen Stapleton Project, 2006-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_101
    - Naomi Rosenblum on Chinese Photography, 2001-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_102
    - Pierpaolo Mittica Project, 2010-2013; FA_MSS_558_ER_103
    - Sounds -- Highway Traffic, Truck Door, Screeches, Crickets, undated (Box 42, Quarter inch audio reel 558.0517)
    - "They Fight with Cameras", 2001-2011; FA_MSS_558_ER_94
    - Tommy Tune Project -- Electronic Records, 2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_104
    - Tommy Tune Project -- Exhibition Footage, 2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_112
    - Unnamed Project -- Boobie in Beth Israel, July 23, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0153)
    - Unnamed Project -- Boobie Out of D, May 29, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0154)
    - Unnamed Project -- Boobie Out of D, May 29, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0150)
    - Unnamed Project -- Dance Rehearsal -- Safespace Gay Pride Parade, June 20, 2000 (Box 22, Minidv 558.0168)
    - Unnamed Project -- Electronic Records, circa 2000-2001; FA_MSS_558_ER_105
    - Unnamed Project -- N22, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0155)
    - Unnamed Project -- NA Meeting -- Nancy's House -- 1 of 2, May 6, 2000 (Box 61, Betacam 558.0005)
    - Unnamed Project -- NA Meeting -- Nancy's House -- Tape 1, May 6, 2000 (Box 33, Dvcpro 558.0461)
    - Unnamed Project -- NA Meeting -- Nancy's House -- Coney Island -- 2 of 2, May 6, 2000 (Box 61, Betacam 558.0006)
    - Unnamed Project -- NA Meeting -- Nancy's House -- Coney Island -- Tape 2, May 6, 2000 (Box 46, Dvcpro 558.0272)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy, May 28, 2001 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0220)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy after Supreme Court, December 15, 2000 (Box 22, Minidv 558.0167)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy and AIDS, July 31, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0158)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy/Andre 2, June 5, 2001 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0218)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy and Boobie -- Andre, June 3, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0156)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy, Carl, George, Raise and Nancy in Office -- Sound Bad, June 19, 2000 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0214)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy and Dennis -- Tape 1 of 2, April 14, 2000 (Box 37, Audiocassette 558.0135)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy and Dennis -- Tape 2 of 2, April 14, 2000 (Box 37, Audiocassette 558.0146)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy and Frank BBQ, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0151)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy and Frank Getting Boobie, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0163)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy and Grandma, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0161)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy Lem Graduation/Humanitarian Awards, June 23, 2000 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0152)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy NA YR 2 JDS, May 20, 2001 (Box 22, Minidv 558.0165)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy NA YR 2 JDS, May 20, 2001 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0216)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy NA YR 2 JDS, May 20, 2001 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0217)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy on Pier -- Tape 1, March 31, 2000 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0164)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy on Pier -- 1 of 2, March 31, 2000 (Box 61, Betacam 558.0007)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy on Pier -- 1 of 2 and Nancy's Three Homeless Kids -- 2 of 2, March 31, 2000 (Box 61, Betacam 558.0008)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy on Pier -- Tapes 1-2/Nancy's 3 Homeless Kids -- Tape 3, undated (Box 38, Vhs 558.0185)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy on Pier with 3 Kids from SafeSpace -- Tape 2, March 31, 2000 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0157)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy, Paul, Kids, Jules, October 1, 2000 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0219)
    - Unnamed Project -- Nancy, Paul, Jules, October 30, 2000 (Box 22, Minidv 558.0166)
    - Unnamed Project -- NF Kids/Court #1 -- Jules, November 13, 2000 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0160)
    - Unnamed Project -- NF Kids/Court #2 -- Jules, November 13, 2000 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0162)
    - Unnamed Project -- NYUDH Debb JDS, November 13, 2001 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0236)
    - Unnamed Project -- Safespace -- Candle Vigil, April 5, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0188)
    - Unnamed Project -- Safespace -- Candle Vigil, April 5, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0195)
    - Unnamed Project -- SafeSpace Gay Pride Parade -- Wendy Bednarz -- Tape 1, June 25, 2000 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0159)
    - Unnamed Project -- SafeSpace Gay Pride Parade -- Tape 2, June 25, 2000 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0213)
    - Unnamed Project -- Safespace -- Webster Hall -- Tape 2, May 7, 2001 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0212)
    - Unnamed Project -- Safespace -- Webster Hall -- Tape 3, May 7, 2001 (Box 34, Minidv 558.0211)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0225)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 62, Audiocassette 558.0231)
    - Untitled -- Submaster, undated (Box 40, Betacam sp 558.0544)